Neil Ranasingha

Software Developer

miran8r@gmail.com
+447450440842
LinkedIn

SUMMARY

I am a software developer with 2 years of experience operating in small to large team environments, working on multiple workflows of varied complexity. Comfortable working both on front and back end Appway technologies, using Spring Boot services to implement and manage microservices and employing Oracle Database to operate on database systems. Skills and knowledge include leading programming tools and techniques such as scrum, the Atlassian suite and Git. I work well in a team, collaborating on complex problem-solving scenarios and breaking them down into simple software solutions that match the client's needs. I am now seeking an opportunity to exploit my current experience and skills in a collaborative environment and to further develop my knowledge and capabilities in the ever expanding world of technology.

KEY SKILLSAppway

Java **OOO**

JavaScript

Python

HTML5

CSS

SQL

C++

00000

Team player

ToolsGit

@@@

00000

Maven

Oracle Database

Visual Studio

Atlassian Suite

WORK EXPERIENCE

Pictet
Technologies

Software Developer

Pictet Technologies SA via FDM, Luxemburg

Sep 2019 - Sep 2021

A technology company focused on building client lifecycle management and back-office automation tools for its sole client - Pictet.

- I successfully implemented multiple new and pre-existing wealth management related business workflows of varied complexity, using the Appway web tool to either convert them from Adobe LiveCycle suite or from paper-based systems into a new single source web app.
- Managed the development and implementation of a high priority workflow to create an
 investment suitability dynamic web form, by gathering business requirements for different
 financial regions, collaborating and communicating cross-functionally and ensuring client
 satisfaction while navigating through ambiguity and working within a tight schedule.
- I created simple to highly complex webapps, using object-oriented programming for both front and back end development of multiple features based on a BPMN web tool.
- Employed Spring Boot integrations to implement and manage numerous microservices to satisfy business requirements. Examples of services created are: conversion of JSON data into XML; processing of user data into appropriate databases based on web app integrations; communication of essential data to other services managed by the business.
- Used Oracle Database to design, build and manage database systems for projects of different size and scope.
- Participated in the release management process and on any improvements related to its operation/automation.
- I contributed to 2 years of the 3-year digital transformation project.
- Worked on 2-week sprint cycles, in a scrum team of 4-6 members, to execute project related tickets, acting as a point of contact for other team members requiring support and presenting/demoing sprint progress at sprint reviews on a rotation basis.



Software Developer

BiNow Ltd, London

Jun 2018 - Jan 2019

A start-up founded by a small group of students, to develop a self-sustained "deal ecosystem" that allows consumers to be notified when a deal that meets their specific criteria is available (e.g. Product, Price, Saving, Category, etc.)

- The role focused on developing a database using MySQL and using Python to program web scrapers to acquire data. Programmed in Java to manipulate the database applying SQL commands to process and prepare the data to be displayed on the prototype mobile app to be developed in the future.
- I was able to learn how to adapt to new technologies and environments straight out of university, as well as further develop the ability to assimilate new programming skills quickly.

More about me

- Photography My dream is to
 travel around the
 world capturing
 its wonders.
- Tech Enthusiast
- Keeping in touch with latest innovations.
- Foodie Love to try new food and learn about cooking cuisines and techniques.
- Italian born with Sri Lankan heritage now living in the UK

EDUCATION



BSc Computer Science - 2:1 (Hons)

University of Lincoln

Sep 2015 - Jun 2018

Modules included:

Problem Solving, Programming and Data Structures, Web Authoring, Object-Oriented Programming, Database Systems, Programming Paradigms, Mobile Computing, Software Engineering and Cross-Platform Development.

REFERENCES

Name	Position	Contact
<u>Laurent Dubuisson</u>	Scrum Master	ldubuisson@pictet-technologies.com
Emma Bourgeois	Business Analyst	embourgeois@pictet.com